Ehsaan Ali

• Islamabad, Pakistan

□ ehsaanalinagyal@gmail.com

\(+92 342 050 79 23

in ehsaanalinagyal

Chsaanali

Summary _

PIAIC Certified AI Developer | Microsoft Certified Python Developer | AI Master's Student at Fast University. Skilled in ML, DL, and data science, I specialize in developing advanced algorithms and models, creating custom data pipelines, and building visualization tools for effective decision-making

Education _

MS FAST NUCES, Isb, Artificial Intelligence

Jan. 2022 to Jan 2024

- GPA: 3.7/4.0 (Gold Medal)
- **Coursework:** Deep Learning, Image Processing, Machine Learning and Big Data Analytics
- **BS SZABIST, Isb**, Software Engineering

Aug. 2017 to Aug 2021

- GPA: 3.26/4.0
- **Coursework:** Web Development, Software Engineering and Artificial Intelligence

Experience _____

FAST NUCES, Lab Instructor (Permanent)

- Isb, Pakistan Sept 2023 to Jan. 2024 10 months
- Conducted Artificial Intelligence BS Labs covering topics search algorithms, BFS, DFS, Greedy search, A star, and some introductory sessions on Machine learning.
- Developing course materials, including lab lectures, lab manuals, assignments, and exams, and employing innovative teaching methods to promote active learning and engagement.
- Facilitate student learning through hands-on activities, lab projects, and class discussions, and provide personalized feedback on student work to support their progress.
- Researcher AIM Research Lab
- Teaching Assistant Research methodology

SZABIST, Lab Instructor (Visiting)

- Conducted Data Structures BS Labs covering different sorting and search algorithms. The labs also focused on implementing different data structures in C++.
- Developing course materials, including lab lectures, lab manuals, assignments, and exams, and employing innovative teaching methods to promote active learning and engagement.
- Facilitate student learning through hands-on activities, lab projects, and class discussions, and provide personalized feedback on student work to support their progress.

Isb, Pakistan Dec. 2023 to Jan. 2024 4 months

Internships Isb, Pakistan

- PHP Laravel Internship at Macro Soar
- Data Science and Business Analytics at Sparks Foundation
- BDO at at Ankasky

Projects _

Activity Recognition

- Developed a Computer vision-based Activity Recognition in COnstruction.
- Used LSTM and CNNs

DeepFake Detection(MS thesis)

- Developed a deep fake detection system using lighting inconsistencies in retinal and face movements.
- Implemented landmark Detection.
- used FacedSwapGAN for deep fake detection.

Automatic Stationary Billing System

- Developed an AI-based Automatic Stationary billing system using YOLO.
- Used Computer Vision algorithms along with Python programming language.

Image Steganography

- Implemented the Enhancement of Encoded Cover in Multi-Image Steganography using Deep Learning
- Used deep learning frameowrks.

Smart YouTube Video Assistant

- Developed a Smart YouTube Video Assistant that allows users to input a YouTube video URL and a custom prompt, generating relevant responses in various formats (plain text, text with images, video snippets, or a video response).
- Enhanced user experience by providing additional recommendations, including related web sources, images, and YouTube videos.

Dementia Classification

• Implemented a classifier to classify dementia using a Structured Dataset

Intelligent Health Monitoring System (FYP BS)

- Implemented an intelligent Health Monitor System as a final-year project.
- Framework : Django python
- Front End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, High Charts API
- · Back End: Python, Regression Algo
- Database : PostgreSQL
- **Role**: Front End Development, Backend Development, Forecasting Using Artificial Intelligence

Additional Courses and Workshops _____

- · Certified Artificial Intelligence from PIAIC
- MTA 98-381 Python Certification
- · AI for everyone Coursera Certification
- Workshop attempt on Agile Methodology

Technologies _

Languages: Python, PHP, SQL, Django, Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpenCV, C, C++, NLTK

Tools and Technologies: Machine Learning, Generative AI, Tableau, Hugging face, Git.